DAVID COLLINS

Junior Full Stack Developer

Github | Linkedin | Portfolio

Cardiff, UK | davemattcoll@gmail.com | +44 78 4248 5049

Executive Summary

I am a junior software developer with skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python all of which are backed-up by a Full Stack Software Development Diploma from the Code Institute. I have worked in the arts and cultural events sector for over a decade, gaining a wealth of professional experience. In addition, I have also enhanced my IT knowledge and skills over the past few years, both for personal and professional purposes, and I am keen to further my development. I am a good communicator, a creative problem solver and a team player who is eager to enter the tech industry and join a stimulating development team where I can grow and contribute.

Education

June 2022 - June 2023 Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (Accredited by Coleg y Cymoedd)

Sept 2006 - Jun 2009 DCU (Dublin City University) Dublin, Ireland

1st Class BA (Hons) - Media Production Management (First Class Honours)

Technical Skill Set

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Version Control
HTML CSS JavaScript Python	MongoDB MySQL	Django Flask jQuery Bootstrap	Git GitHub

Portfolio Projects

- Kokochen Marien Wong Kwok Chuen aka. Kokochen is a freelance illustrator living in Metz, France. This
 portfolio site showcases Marine's illustrations and examples of her work. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS
 & Bootstrap. Link to Github
- Magic 8 Ball- The Magic 8 Ball is used for fortune telling or seeking advice. This is a fun website where users can
 ask the Magic 8 Ball a question and receive a response that affirms or rejects their query. Technologies used to
 build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap. <u>Link to Github</u>
- 3. **Speak EV** Speak EV is a crowdsourced dictionary of terms and jargon related to electric vehicles (EVs). The site allows any visitor to view the dictionary and registered users to add their own terms to it. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Flask, MongoDB & Materialize. Link to Github
- 4. **Got No Beans** GotNoBeans is an online retailer specialising in coffee brewing equipment. They offer a wide variety of home brewers and accessories alongside brewing recipes and event listings for their meet-ups around the UK. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS. JavaScript, Python, Django, ElephantSQL, AWS, Heroku & Bootstrap. Link to Github

Work Experience

Sept 2022 - Present Chapter Arts Centre Duty Manager Cardiff, UK

- Responsible for the operation of all front of house activities including the health & safety of the public & staff.
- Departmental responsibility for customer matters when on duty; managing operations, resolving service issues etc
- Work collaboratively with managers and front-line staff to ensure a consistent and seamless service for visitors.
- Supervise a team of volunteer ushers, housekeeping staff and security personnel when on shift.
- Use specialist ticketing (Spektrix) & event management software (Artifax) to manage tickets sales & event bookings.
- Provide ad-hoc IT support, across all front of house areas, when on-site outside of normal office hours.

Apr 2022 - Sept 2022 Cardiff Council

Housing Solutions Assistant

Cardiff, UK

- Assist the team in providing a comprehensive service to help clients who are homeless or at risk of becoming homeless.
- Process applications for bonds and rent in advance payment to private landlords.
- Help to ensure that properties meet council standards and advise landlords of any work required.
- Securely handle confidential data, complying with the council's policies and procedures.

Feb 2020 - Sept 2021

Triodos Bank

Office Services Co-Worker

Bristol, UK

- Assisted in the delivery of IT, building and office support services at Triodos UK HQ in Bristol.
- Worked closely with a range of 3rd party suppliers and contractors to ensure best possible service.
- Supported the IT team by providing supplementary on-site IT support and in deploying hardware.
- Established process for deployment of IT/office equipment to co-workers to enable remote working.
- Received and actioned building faults, repairing whenever possible.
- Carried out a variety of building maintenance and new installation tasks; including PAT testing.

Certificates/Courses

La Maison de l'amitié - French Language Studies (level 4/B2 certificate)

Additional Information/Interests

- I am currently working on freelance projects...
- Regular engagement on the Code Institute Slack tech forum.
- Fluent English and have an upper intermediate level of French.
- Full A (motorbike) and B (car) driving licences.

References available on request.